As times change, difficult cases will increase in number!
تتضاعف القضايا المعقّدة مع مضيّ خط الوقت
Shinichi's finally back today!
!رجع شينتشي أخيراً اليوم
But something's not quite right!
لكن هناك أمرٌ ليس في محلّه
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
A high school detective from Kansai, Hattori Heiji, suddenly appeared.
ظهر مُتحرّ في الثانوية من كانساي في مكتب العمّ فجأةً يُدعى هاتّوري هيجي
Seems he wants to challenge me, Shinichi.
بدا أنّه يريد منازلتي، أي شينتشي
Just then, a diplomat's wife showed up
وحينذاك، أتت زوجة الدبلوماسيّ تسوجيمورا
and asked for a background check of her son's girlfriend.
وطلبت من العمّ تحرّي خلفية حبيبة ابنها
At her home, we found the diplomat poisoned to death in his study!
وفي منزلها، وجدنا الدبلوماسي ميتاً بالسُم في مكتبه
What's more, it was a locked room murder!
!كما أنّها كانت جريمة غرفة مقفلة
Hattori finds evidence and figures out tricks,
يجد هاتّوري الدلائل توالياً ويكتشف الحيل
but my cold and the alcohol Hattori
لكنّ زكامي والشراب الكحولي الذي أعطاني إيّاه هاتّوري
gave me caused me to collapse!
قادا بي لارتفاع حرارتي وانهياري
But there's something not right about this fever!
لكن هناك أمرٌ غريب في هذه الحُمّى
Something's wrong!
يوجد خطبٌ ما
I'm burning up!
!أشعر بسخونة شديدة
My heart feels like it's gonna burst!
!كأنّ قلبي على وشك الانفجار
Well, Kudo?
إذاً يا كودو؟
If you got any problems with my theory, show yourself!
لو كانت لديك مشكلة مع استنتاجي فأظهر نفسك
Better hurry before I solve it all!
!عليك الإسراع وإلّا سأحلّ كل شيء
So who...
...من يكون
Who's the killer, Hattori-kun?!
من يكون القاتل إذاً يا هاتّوري-كن؟
Not so fast!
على رسلك
What's the deal, Kudo? Forfeiting the match?
ما الخطب يا كودو؟ هل ستنسحب من النزال؟
Fine by me...
لا بأس
C'mon! Hurry!
!هيّا! بسرعة
It'd take at least five or six minutes
سيستغرق قتل الضحيّة وتنفيذ الحيلة
to kill the victim and pull off this trick.
بين 5 إلى 6 دقائق على الأقل
The murder took place in
...وقعت الجريمة
the thirty minutes between 3:30 and 4:00.
في النصف ساعة بين الثالثة والنصف والرابعة
The doctor's here!
!أتى الطبيب
Conan-kun?
كونان-كن؟
His wife is in the clear,
زوجته خارج الشبهات
as she was with us the whole time.
فقد كانت معنا طوال الوقت
Similarly, the butler is in the clear,
وينطبق الأمر على الخادم
as he spoke with neighbors
الذي كان يتكلّم مع الجيران
the whole time at the front door,
في تلك الفترة عند الباب الأمامي
and then greeted us all.
قبل أن يستقبلنا
Hey, where are you, Conan-kun?
أين أنت يا كونان-كن؟
The son and girlfriend are suspicious,
الابن وحبيبته مثيران للشبهة
since they arrived before the wife and left when we arrived,
بما أنّهما وصلا قبل الزوجة بقليل ،ووجدناهما نازلين من الطابق الثاني
but they were gone for only a minute or two.
لكن لم يلبثا هناك إلا دقيقة أو اثنتين
Not enough time.
فلا وقت لارتكاب الجريمة
Where did Conan-kun run off to?
...أين ذهب كونان-كن
Conan-kun! Where are you?
كونان-كن! أين أنت؟
Which leaves just the old man
...ما يترك لنا
who arrived after 2:00 and watched TV in the next room over!
الشخص الذي وصل بعد الثانية وشاهد التلفاز ...في الغرفة المجاورة للمكتب
I found proof in the Japanese-style room...
...وجدتُ الدليل في الغرفة يابانية الطراز
...the fishing line!
!خيط صيد سمك
This is the latest and strongest type of fishing line!
هذا أحدث وأقوى نوع من خيوط الصيد
You're a fisherman; don't pretend to play dumb!
!أنت صيّاد سمك فلا تتظاهر بالجهل
Plus, on our way to this room, we ran into you at the stairs...
...كما أنّنا صادفناك في طريقنا مع الزوجة للمكتب
Please wait in the Japanese-style room.
انتظر في غرفة الضيافة يابانية الطراز رجاءً
In short, you were in the Japanese-style room after the murder.
أي أنّك كنت في الغرفة يابانية الطراز بعد الجريمة
The fact this fishing line was in the garbage is immutable proof!
وجود خيط الصيد هذا في حاوية قمامة !تلك الغرفة دليلٌ دامغ
Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن
Well?! Am I wrong?!
!إذاً؟ أأنا مخطئ؟
Excuse me, but has Conan-kun been here?
المعذرة، هل رأيتما كونان-كن هنا؟
No...
...كلا
Old man!
!أيّها العجوز
Yes. It was me...
صحيح، كان أنا
I win!
!فزت
I was the one who killed my son Isao--
...كنتُ من قتل ابني إيساو
Nope, I'm afraid not.
كلا، ليس صحيحاً
What?!
!ماذا؟
You got it all wrong!
ليس صحيحاً البتّة
Kudo!
!كودو
Shinichi...
...شينتشي
So this is Kudo... Kudo Shinichi!
!هذا كودو... كودو شينتشي
It's... It's really Shinichi...
...إنّه... إنّه شينتشي حقّاً
Shinichi...
...شينتشي
Where were you?!
!أين كنت؟
You suddenly disappear and then reappear!
!تختفي فجأةً وتظهر فجأةً
I was... I was so worried!
!كنت... كنت قلقةً جداً
Quit cryin, dummy.
لا تبكي يا حمقاء
Gimme a break!
!اسكت
She's right!
معها حقّ
You show up now and say I'm wrong?
تظهر فجأةً وتطعن بكلامي؟
Are you suggesting my theory is faulty?!
أترى نقصاً في استنتاجي؟
Hold on, Ran.
...انتظري يا ران
You're sweating...
...أنت تتعرّق
It'll be over soon...
سأنتهي بسرعة
Shinichi?
شينتشي؟
What's wrong with my theory, Kudo?!
!أين الخطأ في استنتاجي يا كودو؟
The trick you just explained is armchair theory.
الحيلة التي شرحتَها نظرية لا عملية
It's 100% impossible!
%أي مستحيلة 100
S-Say what?!
ما-ماذا؟
Hold on, Kudo-kun.
انتظر يا كودو-كن
I hate to interrupt,
،أكره المقاطعة
but his locked room trick works perfectly!
لكن حيلة الغرفة المقفلة التي أشار لها تعمل بإتقان
We even tested it out with my own pants!
اختبرناها قبل قليل ببنطالي
You take a needle-ended line,
تأخذ خيطاً بطرف مربوط بإبرة بدايةً
tape the other end to the key holder,
،وتلصق الطرف الآخر بحمّالة المفتاح
and put the needle end through the pants pocket from the inside.
ثمّ تمرر طرف الإبرة عبر جيب البنطال من الداخل
Then you pull both ends outside the room, lock the door,
،وتسحب الطرفين خارج الغرفة وتقفل الباب
and by pulling the needle end...
...ثمّ بسحبك لطرف الإبرة
...the key will enter the pocket on its own!
سيدخل المفتاح الجيب من تلقاء نفسه...
One last tug and the line breaks free of the tape.
...وبسحبة أخيرة
Then, by simply winding it up, the evidence disappears
وكلّ ما يبقى هو ربط الخيط وسيختفي الدليل
and creates a locked room!
وتنشأ الغرفة المقفلة
Is the key really in your pocket, Inspector Megure?
هل المفتاح داخل جيبك حقاً يا مفتّش ميغوري؟
I heard the key was in a double pocket in the victim's pants...
سمعتُ أنّ المفتاح كان في جيب مزدوج لبنطال الضحيّة
Y-Yes...
...أ-أجل
Of course it is!
!بالطبع
If you think we're lying, see for yourself!
!إن ظننت أنّنا نكذب فانظر بنفسك
See?! It's in his double--
...أترى؟ إنّه في جيب
That... can't be!
!لا... يمكن
I'm certain I put the line through his double pocket!
!أنا متأكد أني مررت الخيط عبر جيبه المزدوج
It was because Inspector Megure was sitting when you put the key in.
ذلك لأنّ المفتّش ميغوري كان جالساً عندما أدخلت المفتاح
What?!
!ماذا؟
Because he was sitting,
،لأنّه كان جالساً
the pocket folded and blocked the key's path,
،انطوى الجيب وحجب طريق المفتاح
and the tape came off before it could get into the double pocket.
ونُزع الشريط قبل أن يصل الجيب المزدوج
Plus the victim was heavyset, just like Inspector Megure.
كما أنّ الضحيّة كان مليئاً مثل المفتّش ميغوري
Now that you mention it,
...بذكرك ذلك
when I put my hand in the victim's pocket...
...عندما أدخلتُ يدي في جيب الضحية
Damn, his pants are tight.
تبّاً، بنطاله ضيّق
But it could happen 1 in 10,000-- no, 1 in 10 times!
...لكن يمكن أن يحصل ذلك في مرّة من 10 آلاف كلا، مرّة من 10 مرات
The result would always be the same.
ستبقى النتيجة نفسها مهما حاولت
Recall the key's direction when it was in the victim's double pocket.
تذكّر اتّجاه المفتاح عندما كان في الجيب المزدوج لبنطال الضحيّة
The key's direction?
اتّجاه المفتاح؟
Yes. Even if it did get in his double pocket 1 in 10,000 times,
صحيح، حتّى لو دخل الجيب في مرّة من 10 آلاف
it would only be the key holder.
ستدخل الحمّالة فحسب
The key couldn't possibly flip over to join the key holder in the pocket.
لا يمكن أن ينقلب المفتاح ويدخل مع الحمّالة في الجيب الضيق
The fact the key was fully inside
وجوده بالكامل في الدّاخل
means the killer put it in the double pocket beforehand.
يعني أنّ القاتل وضعه في جيب الضحية سلفاً
Then what about this needle-ended fishing line I found?!
ماذا عن خيط الصيد بالإبرة الذي وجدتُه إذاً؟
Another trap set by the killer to place the blame on the old man.
فخّ آخر نصبه القاتل لإلقاء اللوم على العجوز
I found a handful of others all throughout the house.
وجدتُ أشياء أخرى مشابهة في أرجاء المنزل
The killer planted them in other rooms, too.
وضعها القاتل في بقيّة الغرف أيضاً
So that it wouldn't matter where the old man was during the murder.
كيلا يهم أين كان العجوز وقت وقوع الجريمة
But he admitted to the crime!
!لكنّه اعترف بارتكاب الجريمة
He simply stepped into the killer's trap, knowingly.
دخل فخّ القاتل من محض إرادته فحسب
Though I don't know why.
رغم أنّي أجهل السبب
This room was completely locked!
كانت هذه الغرفة مقفلة تماماً
You're not suggesting it was suicide?!
لا تقترح أنّه كان انتحاراً، صحيح؟
No, it wasn't suicide.
كلا، لم يكن انتحاراً
Plus the killer's real trick is still here.
كما أنّ حيلة القاتل الحقيقية لا تزال هنا
Real trick?
الحيلة الحقيقية؟
Have you forgotten?
أنسيت؟
When you discovered the victim,
،عندما اكتشفتم الجثّة
an opera was playing in the room
كانت هناك أوبرا تُعزف في الغرفة
and there were books stacked next to the victim.
كما كتباً متراصّة بجواره
The opera was to drown out the victim's possible screams
كان الهدف من الأوبرا عزل صرخات الضحيّة
after being poisoned with the needle.
التي قد تصدر بعد تسميمه بالإبرة
The books were to hide his possibly-contorted face.
والكتب لإخفاء وجهه المعصور بالألم غالباً
Yeah, right!
!مستحيل
Whose eyes and ears needed to be fooled?!
لخداع أعين وآذان من؟
Hattori... Yours!
!كان الهدف... أنت يا هاتّوري
Say what?!
!ماذا؟
Not just you.
ليس أنت فحسب
None of the others who came in with you noticed, either.
لم ينتبه المتحرّي موري وران اللذان أتيا معك أيضاً
Wait, you don't mean--!
...لحظة، أتقصد
When you entered the study,
،عندما دخلتم المكتب
the first one to approach the victim...
...أوّل من اقترب من الضحيّة
Yes! The killer... was you!
!أجل، القاتل هو... أنت
Yes! The killer...
...أجل، القاتل
...was you, Madam!
!هو أنت يا سيّدة
She killed her husband?!
قتلت السيّدة زوجها؟
You can't be serious!
!لا يُعقل
You mean the victim was still alive then?
أتقصد أنّ الضحيّة كان لا يزال حيّاً آنذاك؟
Yes. She had only knocked him out with drugs or something.
أجل، أفقدته وعيه فحسب سلفاً بعقار ما
Then she poisoned him with the needle when pretending to wake him.
ثمّ سمّمته بالإبرة وهي تتظاهر بإيقاظه
But it was only natural that no one noticed.
رغم أنّه من الطبيعي أنّ أحداً لم ينتبه
If the sleeping drug and the poison were both powerful enough...
...إذا كان العقار المنوّم والسم قويّين بما يكفي
...the victim would die immediately after being pricked, as if asleep.
سيموت الضحيّة فوراً بعد وخزه كما لو كان نائماً
She set up the opera and the books just in case.
جهّزت الأوبرا والكتب تحسّباً
But if this sleeping drug turned up in an autopsy,
...لكن إذا ظهرت آثار العقار المنوّم في التشريح
this trick would've...
...ستُكشف الحيلة
No, we wouldn't know.
كلا، لن تُكشف
We assumed he was dead before we entered.
افترضنا أنّه كان ميتاً قبل دخولنا
We only would've known he was knocked out before he was killed.
كنا لنعرف أنّه أُفقد وعيه قبل تعرضه للقتل وحسب
In other words, this was a psychological locked room murder,
،أي أنّها كانت جريمة قتل غرفة مقفلة ذهنية
based on our assumption that no one would ever invite a detective
مبنيّة على افتراض أنّ لا أحد سيدعو مُتحرّياً
to a locked room and then kill someone in it!
!لغرفة مقفلة ثم يقتل أحداً داخلها
That what you wanna say, Kudo?
ذاك ما تريد قوله يا كودو، صحيح؟
Yeah...
أجل
Then let's see some proof!
هلّا أريتنا دليلاً إذاً؟
Plus, I didn't see her pull out a poisoned needle!
كما أنّي لم أرها تخرج إبرة مسمومة آنذاك
Yes. She took out the needle
أجل، أخرجت الإبرة
in a way that no one would notice.
بطريقة لا ينتبه لها أحد
Together with her key!
مع المفتاح
H-Her key?!
الـ-المفتاح؟
Yeah. Her key holder is of the same design as the victim's.
أجل، لحمّالة مفتاحها نفس تصميم حمّالة مفتاح الضحيّة
Naturally, hers should also split in two.
يُفترض أن تنفصل حمّالتها طبيعياً أيضاً
Now then,
...إذاً
please show us your key and the inside of your key holder!
هلّا أريتِنا مفتاحك وحمّالته وما بها رجاءً؟
If you don't mind, Madam...
...سيّدتي، سأتفقدها قليلاً
W-What is this groove?!
ما هذا الخطّ؟
The poison needle was likely stored in it.
وُضعت الإبرة المسمومة به غالباً
She customized it so she could pull it out right after entering the room.
عدّلت الحمّالة كي يمكنها إخراج الإبرة فور دخولنا الغرفة
In short, that very key holder
أي أنّ حمّالة المفتاح هذه
is definitive proof that she is the killer!
!هي دليل دامغ بأنّها القاتلة
But why would she kill her husband?!
لكن لمَ قد تقتل زوجها؟
If my hunch is correct,
،إن أصاب حدسي
her motive is in this photograph.
فدافعها موجود في هذه الصورة غالباً
This is from when she was still young...
هذه صورة من شبابها
Look closer, Inspector.
أمعن النظر سيّدي المفتّش
Doesn't she look like someone?
ألا تشبه أحداً؟
She looks just like Yukiko-san!
!تبدو مثل يوكيكو-سان
That's absurd!
!لا يُعقل
See? Only her hair is a different color!
انظروا، لون شعرها مختلف فحسب
Of course she looks like me.
بالطبع تشبهني
I'm... Yukiko's mother!
!فأنا... أمّ يوكيكو
Eh?!
!ما-ماذا؟
T-That can't be!
!لا-لا يمكن
Then you had her with your husband, Isao-san?
هذه ابنة من زوجك إيساو-سان إذاً؟
No. Yukiko is my daughter from my previous marriage.
كلا، أنجبتُ يوكيكو من زواجي السابق
Yes! She's the daughter of Yamashiro Kenji, a diplomat outcast
أجل! إنّها ابنة ياماشيرو كينجي، دبلوماسي نُبذ من المجتمع
from society by my current husband Tsujimura Isao twenty years ago!
!على يد زوجي الحالي تسوجيمورا إيساو قبل 20 عاماً
Yamashiro Kenji?!
ياماشيرو كينجي؟
Yes, the man who died in prison twenty years ago.
أجل، الرجل الذي مات في السجن قبل 20 عاماً
Tsujimura's goal was to get rid of him,
كان هدف تسوجيمورا التخلّص منه
since he was a rival diplomat!
!بما أنّه كان منافساً له
And then to obtain me as his wife!
!ثمّ أخذني زوجةً له
My husband was arrested,
اُعتقل زوجي
and Yukiko was adopted by his family.
ثمّ تبنّت عائلته يوكيكو
Having hit rock bottom mentally,
...بعد انهياري الذهني
I... I broke up with my wife just for you.
انفصلتُ عن زوجتي لأجلك
Tsujimura cajoled me,
،تقرّب لي تسوجيمورا
and I wound up wife to that devilish man!
وأصبحتُ زوجةً لذاك الرجل الشيطان
I realized it all when Takayoshi-san brought home a photo of Yukiko.
أدركتُ كلّ شيء عندما جلب تاكايوشي-سان صورة حبيبته يوكيكو للمنزل
At first, I thought it was just an uncanny resemblance, but Tsujimura...
...ظننتُه مجرد تشابه عابر بدايةً، لكنّ تسوجيمورا
Never! I refuse to let him be with the daughter of that man!
كلا! مستحيل أن أترك تاكايوشي !يرتبط بابنة ذاك الرجل أبداً
Shocked, I continued to press him,
...شككتُ وضغطتُ عليه
and he started to talk about how he framed Yamashiro for corruption.
فبدأ يتكلّم عن إلفاقه تهمة الفساد بياماشيرو
And that his father had assisted with it.
وعن مساعدة أبيه له
I'm sorry, Kimie-san.
آسف يا كيمي-سان
I wasn't thinking straight back then...
لم أكن أفكر برشد آنذاك
I see.
فهمت
You purposely took her bait to try to make up for your past...
وطأت فخّ السيّدة متقصّداً للتكفير عن خطيئتك في الماضي
There is no use in pretending to be good, Father.
لا جدوى من التظاهر بالصلح الآن يا أبتاه
Because he left this life as an innocent man who was framed.
لأنّه فارق هذا العالم رجلاً بريئاً لُفّقت له تهمة
Takayoshi-san.
تاكايوشي-سان
Y-Yes?
أ-أجل؟
I know I'm not fit to say this now,
لا أملك حقّ قول هذا الآن
but please take care of Yukiko.
لكن اعتن بيوكيكو رجاءً
Y-Yeah...
...نـ-نعم
Ah. So she was harsh with her daughter
هكذا إذاً، كانت قاسيةً مع ابنتها
so that she wouldn't realize.
كيلا تدرك علاقتهما
Hey, Kudo!
!كودو
Shinichi!
!شينتشي
Are you okay, Shinichi?!
!أأنت بخير يا شينتشي؟
Yeah, it's just my cold...
...أجل، إنّه زكامي فحسب
But how'd you know all those details about the case?
لكن كيف عرفت تفاصيل هذه القضيّة؟
You had to have been spying from nearby...
...لا بدّ أنّك كنت تتجسس بالقرب
Get real. That kid with the glasses told me on the phone.
أحمق، أخبرني ذاك الفتى ذو النظّارات على الهاتف
You mean Conan-kun?!
تقصد كونان-كن؟
Yeah...
أجل
Said there was a weird detective from Osaka and to come right away.
قال أنّ هناك متحرّياً غريباً من أوساكا ...وعليّ القدوم فوراً
S-S-So I finished up the case I was on, hopped on a train--
لـ-لـ-لذا أنهيتُ القضية التي كنت ...أعمل عليها سريعاً وصعدتُ القطار
Liar!
!كاذب
He told me it's weird that you don't ask how I am on the phone!
أخبرني هذا الشاب أنّ من الغريب !عدم سؤالك عن حالتي على الهاتف
You were actually nearby, weren't you?
كنت بالقرب في الواقع، صحيح؟
I bet you were watching how worried I was and laughing!
!أنا واثقة أنك كنت تراقبني وأنا قلقة وتضحك
Hey, now, Ran!
...مهلك، ران
Why would you do that?!
لمَ تفعل ذلك؟
I'm this... this...
...أنا... أنا بهذا
Don't underestimate me, now.
لا تستهيني بي
I'm a detective.
أنا مُتحرٍّ
I can tell plenty just from your voice.
يمكنني أن أعرف الكثير من صوتك فحسب
Shinichi! Hold on! I'll go get the doctor!
!شينتشي! انتظر، سأستدعي الطبيب
So my reasoning was wrong from the very start...
كان استنتاجي خاطئاً من البداية إذاً
I lose in every which way this time.
خسرتُ في كلّ جانب هذه المرّة
You're good, Kudo.
أنتَ بارع يا كودو
Your logic's one level above mine.
منطِقُك يفوقني بمستوى
Don't be dumb.
لا تكن أحمقاً
There's no winning, losing, above, or below when it comes to logic...
...لا فوز ولا خسارة، ولا فوق ولا أسفل في المنطق
After all... there's always only one truth...
ففي النهاية.. الحقيقة واحدة دوماً
That's true.
معك حق
Guess I was so focused on our match that I lost my cool.
يبدو أنّي انشغلتُ بمنافستنا ففقدتُ رزانتي
Hey, Kudo! Are you sure it's just a cold?!
كودو! أأنت متأكد أنّه زكام فقط؟
Kudo!
!كودو
Hey, Kudo! You alright?!
!كودو! أأنت بخير؟
Hurry, Doctor!
!طبيب، بسرعة
N-Not good...
...تـ-تبّاً
Hey, Kudo!
!كودو، أنت
My heart again!
!قلبي مُجدداً
I'm burning up!
!أنا أحترق
It's like my bones are melting!
...كأنّ عظامي تذوب
Hey! Kudo!
!كودو
Don't tell me I'm turning back...
...أيمكن أنّي سأرجع
After I finally returned to normal!
!بعدما عدت لجسدي الطبيعي أخيراً
Am I turning back into that kid... into Conan again?!
!هل سأتحوّل لذاك الصبيّ... كونان مُجدداً؟
Shinichi!
!شينتشي
R-Ran!
!ر-ران
You know you shouldn't be moving around!
!لا يصحّ بك الحركة
You're sick!
!أنت مريض
Oh no! If I turn into Conan now,
...هذا سيّئ، إذا تحوّلتُ لكونان الآن
Ran will discover my identity...
...ستكتشف
Shinichi!
!شينتشي
It's just his coat! Shinichi!
!هذا معطفه فحسب! شينتشي
Please! Don't make me turn back!
!أرجوك! لا ترجعني
At least let me tell Ran...
...دعني أخبر ران على الأقل
Shinichi!
!شينتشي
...with my real mouth
...بفمي الحقيقي
and my real voice...
وصوتي الحقيقي
...just one last thing!
!أمر أخير فحسب
Shinichi?!
!شينتشي؟
From in there?!
من هناك؟
Shinichi!
!شينتشي
Conan-kun?
كونان-كن؟
Where were you?! I looked all over! And where'd you get that shirt?
أين كنت؟ بحثت عنك! كما من أين لك هذا القميص؟
Oh, I was all sweaty,
كنتُ متعرّقاً بشدة
so I borrowed this from that room...
فاستعرتُه من تلك الغرفة
Say, have you seen Shinichi?
أخبرني، هل رأيت شينتشي؟
Shinichi-niichan said he remembered a new case and...
قال شينتشي-نيتشان أنّه تذكر قضيّةً جديدة
Eh?
غيّر ثيابه وغادر من الباب الأمامي
That jerk!
!ذاك الوغد
And he also said not to tell anyone he was involved with this case...
كما قال عليكم ألّا تخبروا أحداً ...بتدخله في هذه القضية
H-Hey! Conan-kun!
!لـ-لحظة، كونان-كن
Conan-kun?!
!كونان-كن؟
After that, I was in bed for three days straight.
لازمتُ الفراش 3 أيام بعد ذلك
During that time, Hattori Heiji went back to Osaka,
وفي تلك الفترة رجع هاتّوري هيجي إلى أوساكا
and thanks to my request to Ran right before I fainted,
،وبفضل طلبي من ران قبل أن يُغمى علي
Kudo Shinichi's name didn't appear in the papers.
لم يظهر اسم كودو شينتشي في الصحف بشأن القضيّة
Now the men in black who shrunk me won't find out I'm alive.
هكذا لن يكتشف الرجال ذوو الرداء الأسود الذين قلّصوا جسدي أنّني حيّ
But how did I turn back into my high school form?
لكن كيف رجعتُ لجسدي من المدرسة الثانوية؟
Wait a minute! As I recall, he showed up, and then...
...لحظة، وفقما أذكر... أتى ذاك الشخص، ثمّ
And then I drank that alcohol he brought!
!ثمّ شربتُ الساكي الذي جلبه
That's it!
!هذه هي
That's gotta be it!
!لا شكّ في الأمر
I turned back by drinking that alcohol!
!رجعتُ لطبيعتي بشربي لذاك الساكي
Alright! There's still a lot left!
حسنٌ، لا يزال هناك الكثير
One drink caused that!
سببت جرعة واحدة ذلك
If I drink this all, I can turn back completely!
!إذا شربتُ هذا كلّه سأعود لطبيعتي كليّاً
Hey, you!
!ولد
What're you drinking, Conan-kun?!
!ما الذي تشربه يا كونان-كن؟
Just as I thought! Alcohol!
!كما ظننت، ساكي
You know kids aren't supposed to drink alcohol!
لا يمكن للصغار شرب ساكي، تعرف ذلك
Don't be stupid! I'm a 2nd-year high schooler!
حمقاء، أنا في السنة الثانية من الثانوية
Wait, that's still underage...
...لحظة، لا أزال قاصراً
Hurry and change your clothes.
أسرع وغيّر ملابسك
Your friends are here!
أتى أصدقاؤك
Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن
Conan!
!كونان
Not you guys again...
...أنتم مجدداً
We were so worried!
!شعرنا بالقلق
You were sick for three days!
مرضتَ بالزكام لثلاثة أيام
You're so lucky you could skip school.
يا لحظّك بتغيّبك عن المدرسة
Maybe I'll catch a cold, too!
ربما سأُصاب بالزكام بدوري
You'll never catch a cold, Genta-kun!
يستحيل أن يصيبك الزكام يا غينتا-كن
Why's that?
لمَ؟
It's like they say, "Stupid people don't catch--"
..."ألا تعرف مقولة "لا يُصيب الأغبياء الزكام
It's good that you're back to normal now!
!من الرائع أنّك عدت لطبيعتك
Man, I'm back to how I was...
...أجل، رجعت لطبيعتي
So why do we have to go to the library now?
أخبروني، لمَ علينا الذهاب للمكتبة الآن؟
You're the only one who hasn't turned in a book report for class!
أنت الوحيد الذي لم يسلّم !تقرير كتاب في الفصل
So we figured we'd help you out! Right?
لذا فكّرنا بمساعدتك، صحيح؟
Yeah!
!أجل
Whatever. Genta and Mitsuhiko are just sticking with Ayumi-chan...
قد يكون هذا هو الحال مع أيومي، ولكن ماذا عن غينتا وميتسوهيكو؟
But I guess I should go with 'em.
لكن ربما سأرافقهم
Once I drink that alcohol and turn back into a high school student,
بعدما أشرب ذاك الساكي وأرجع طالباً في المدرسة الثانوية
I might never get to hang out with them again...
قد لن أستطيع التسكّع معهم هكذا مُجدداً
Actually, Tamada-san has been missing since two nights ago.
في الواقع، تامادا-سان مفقود منذ ليلتين
I-Idiot! Don't turn the lights on!
!حـ-حمقى! لا تشعلوا الأنوار
That's it! I know where the body is hidden!
!وجدتُه! مكان إخفاء الجثّة
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
"The Library Murder Case."
جريمة قتل المكتبة
Next Conan's Hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Backwards Book.
كتاب بغلاف مجلّد
Is next episode Conan's last case?
الحلقة القادمة، أهي القضيّة الأخيرة لكونان؟
The Detective Boys are immortal.
!فرقة فتيان التحرّي منيعة